<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-18T22:19:21-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/feed.xml</id><title type="html">lqb2 spiritual formation (project)</title><subtitle>this is me following my own journey and sharing it with you</subtitle><entry><title type="html">my clearness committee meeting (11 aug 2019)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/08/14/clearness-committee/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="my clearness committee meeting (11 aug 2019)" /><published>2019-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/08/14/clearness-committee</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/08/14/clearness-committee/">&lt;p&gt;so this past sunday was my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.couragerenewal.org/clearnesscommittee&quot;&gt;clearness committee meeting&lt;/a&gt;. the prep work was three stages/bridges:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bridge 1: review my healing action plan. what have i achieved? what is still in progress? what haven’t i accomplished (yet)?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bridge 2: review all my spiritual reports. what am i noticing?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;bridge 3: discernment meeting (using the quaker clearness committee practice) based on the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What is the area of my life I am drawn toward greater connection to the sacred&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Who am I being called to be in this area&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What gets in the way&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What steps might I take to move through obstacles into a new way of being&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;over the past few weeks, i’ve been digging in (not as much as i wanted to, but still a good bit) and really seeing that i’ve done quite a lot. in order to get to sharing about the committee meeting, i’ll skip some of those insights for now, but there’s some good stuff in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when i got down to answering the above questions, here’s what i came up with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the area of my life I am drawn toward greater connection to the sacred&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;men’s healing work, with a focus on queer men of color but not exclusively&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;being grounded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who am I being called to be in this area&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a healer and a facilitator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What gets in the way&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Needing money&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lack of focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What steps might I take to move through obstacles into a new way of being&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moving towards a living situation and financial setup that allow me to do more healing work without needing to ask people for money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as i came to the end of filling in the questions, all sorts of doubts arose. “maybe i’m making up all these answers just to finish the assignments. maybe there’s something deeper, something beneath all these answers, something i should really be digging in towards.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- then a few things happened: 

1. eroc gave me a call a few hours before the meeting and gave me lots of really beautiful feedback about what he's seen in me since this process began. it affirmed lots of the answers i'd written up 
2. luana called and left a magical, affirming voicemail.  --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so when the time for my committee meeting came, i brought in all those answers and the doubts, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i won’t recount the whole call, but essentially the following insights are my takeaways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;instead of holding my doubts as “is this made up vs is this true/not made up,” what if i held the frame that &lt;em&gt;everything is made up because reality is based on our perception&lt;/em&gt;. in that case, if the answers i “made up” are that i am being called to men’s healing work… then that’s as real as anything else.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what i’m being called to in this moment may not be the same thing i feel called towards later. i can make that decision when it arises (but it’s actually not possible to make that choice before the choice point arrives).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(eroc also said this) one of the authentic/integral parts of my healing work for others is that it is almost always rooted in what i need for myself. this is part of how i stay balanced in my “giving” and “receiving.” this is a critical balance to maintain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;two things in particular get me most excited about men’s (healing) work:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;men hugging each other (like for real holding each other)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;men who are closeted being able to come further and further into themselves and out of shame/fear.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i love working in/with groups, though 1:1 is where my eyes light up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;my aries energy, the energy of the initiator is very very real.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO! that’s that for now. thanks, again, yall for supporting me and i’m excited to see what the final 2 months of this program hold. it looks like my group’s last official call is oct 27. what a ride it’s been. and when it ends, i know it’ll still just be a new beginning…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">so this past sunday was my clearness committee meeting. the prep work was three stages/bridges:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a story about the impact of libations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/08/13/libations-in-july/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a story about the impact of libations" /><published>2019-08-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/08/13/libations-in-july</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/08/13/libations-in-july/">&lt;p&gt;a few weeks ago, luana (w/ me on assist) opened a meeting with some ritual work. lu invited me in to lead libations while she rang her bell. it happened and felt good, but the real thing i wanted to write about is this: kathy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;two things happened for her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;first, she shared with us that during the libations sections where i was pouring for future ancestors, the baby kicked. and then kicked during every other mention of ancestors but didn’t kick during any other sections! #shook&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;second, she shared that the part of the libations where i called in visions and dreams of the future had a supercharged impact later. that night she had a dream where a friend of hers (a friend who died of cancer two months ago) wanted her to tell his widow that she should “not be afraid to let her light shine a little brighter.” that next morning, that friend popped up in kathy’s IG feed and kathy relayed the message and it was received really well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;obviously this was lu and me (and all the ancestors and elements and universe) together but still pretty wild for me to be a part of something like that. phew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#shook #shook #shook&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">a few weeks ago, luana (w/ me on assist) opened a meeting with some ritual work. lu invited me in to lead libations while she rang her bell. it happened and felt good, but the real thing i wanted to write about is this: kathy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Horoscopes for the New Moon in Leo – August 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/horoscope/2019/08/04/new-moon-in-leo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Horoscopes for the New Moon in Leo – August 2019" /><published>2019-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/horoscope/2019/08/04/new-moon-in-leo</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/horoscope/2019/08/04/new-moon-in-leo/">&lt;p&gt;source: https://chaninicholas.com/horoscopes-for-the-new-moon-in-leo-2019/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;aries&quot;&gt;Aries&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;basic personality &amp;amp; ego&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the best of my ability, I make room for joy. I defend my right to it. I guard it against being overtaken with the many distractions of the world. I know that being able to be playful is a privilege – one that fear, insecurity, and sorrow swallow when given the chance. There have been many times, a million moments, where I couldn’t access what felt good. When I’ve had to spend all of my energy surviving. When I was worn out by just trying to get through the day. Whatever distance I have from pain, I promise to pursue what brings me healing so that I have more space for hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One moment of pleasure can rewire my entire system, so I treat it as my most sacred of medicines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this new moon, I plant the seeds for future joy to spring forth. I clear what clutters my path to it. I make no exceptions for those that say one thing and do another. I have no patience for anyone that takes what they want from me but offers little to nothing in return. I make sure that I don’t follow those that lead with only their needs in mind. With this new moon, I recommit to my growth through the most enjoyable avenues available. With this new moon, I remember that my prosperity is made more bountiful when shared with the world around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;aquarius-rising&quot;&gt;Aquarius Rising&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;how others experience me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every moment of intimacy I experience burns away a layer of what prevents me from feeling lovable. Any lies about my worthiness that I have picked up, made up, or bought into can be dispelled by a sincere act of kindness. Disrupted by direct transmission of care. Derailed by an act of generosity towards me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make sure to receive them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new moon highlights the relationships in my life that are abundant in their ability to know that love is its own reward. There is nothing to get from each other, just experiences to give and receive. There is nothing to demand of one another when boundaries are respected and beauty is honored. There is nothing to push anyone else towards when I am as firm as I need to be with what is important to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no fear that those that share what I find sacred will find me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this new moon, I remember the power of enjoying the company I keep. I surround myself with those that want to place mutual pleasure side by side with respect and integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;virgo&quot;&gt;Virgo&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;moon: inner self &amp;amp; deepest emotions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I break for joy. I stop when it’s been too long since my body felt loved, replenished, and rested. I pause for all things that help me live my best life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all that I give, offer, and make myself available to, I am allowed to receive, accept, and let myself be. With this new moon, I take some of my best advice. I remember all of the love I have put on others and I put the same on myself. I recall the energy I have spent on building my outer life and reinvest it in doing some inner maintenance. I know how important it is to reconnect with myself through the potent activity of not giving AF while not doing AFing thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am worthy of a reset. I am worth resting for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this new moon, I remember my inherent value. Separate from my production schedule. Separate from my bank account. Separate from what I can do for others. With this new moon, I focus on valuing my free-time, my natural state of being, and all my rituals for restoration and renewal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cancer&quot;&gt;Cancer&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;chiron description from &lt;a href=&quot;https://cafeastrology.com/chiron.html&quot;&gt;cafe astrology&lt;/a&gt;. shout out to luana for suggesting i look up where chiron is in my chart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Chiron is a comet with a unique and erratic orbit. In the natal chart, Chiron is symbolized by the “wounded healer”. It represents our deepest wound, and our efforts to heal the wound. Chiron was named after the centaur in Greek mythology who was a healer and teacher who, ironically, could not heal himself.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Chiron in Astrology: Chiron in our natal charts points to where we have healing powers as the result of our own deep spiritual wounds. We may over-compensate in these areas of life. Chiron, as a wounded healer, first must face issues of low self-worth and feelings of inadequacy and learn to rise above these issues. Because the wound goes deep, and we may work hard to overcome the wound, healing powers are potent.”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I magnetize the materials I need to build my dreams. I cleanse my mind of toxic ideas about amassing wealth for my gain alone. I clear my heart of the misconceptions that I need to cling to, hold on to, or hoard attention and societal recognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that the more I share, the more I have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I make space for what is honestly abundant in my life. Cheap renditions of affluence are no match for the power of generosity. I know that I have been gifted with a bank of goodwill and I plan on spending every cent of it before I leave this earth. I know that I have been given every tool I could ever need and I plan on putting them to the best use. I know that if I don’t focus on innovating how I do my work, I won’t feel alive when I do it. In order to experience abundance, I have to know what things in life can be risked abundantly. My pride, my ego, and any feelings of superiority I may harbor can all be risked, disrupted, and interrupted for a greater wealth to illuminate my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I willingly dismantle any false beliefs that tell me I need to be greedy in order to be wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">source: https://chaninicholas.com/horoscopes-for-the-new-moon-in-leo-2019/</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">some quick thoughts on liberation and self-care</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/07/30/thoughts-on-liberation-and-self-care/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="some quick thoughts on liberation and self-care" /><published>2019-07-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/07/30/thoughts-on-liberation-and-self-care</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/07/30/thoughts-on-liberation-and-self-care/">&lt;p&gt;a few quick quotes and thoughts i’m having while reading &lt;em&gt;my grandmother’s hands&lt;/em&gt; by resmaa menakem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;a calm, settled body is the foundation for health, for healing, for helping others, and for changing the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;a settled body can help other bodies to settle themselves. an unsettled body can push other bodies to be unsettled. (briefer version: a settled body can settle other bodies. an unsettled body can unsettle other bodies.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;because of these two things, i’m now thinking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;caring for myself is not an option. it is foundational. i cannot heal myself or others without knowing how to settle (and activate) my body. i cannot do what is needed without a settled body.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;liberation is not “over there” or “coming up soon.” it is in moments and experiences. liberation, like life, is in the body (ht &lt;a href=&quot;http://infinitegrowth.rocks/blog/2019/3/2/life-is-in-the-body&quot;&gt;dcc&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;harriet tubman said “my people are free.” she knew it and saw it and worked to make it so. i know of people in chains and personally know people in prisons who are free. freedom is joy without fear. therefore, contrary to lots of dominant rhetoric, i do not believe “none of us are free until all of us are free.” i believe that when one surpasses fear of death, you can be free while staring down the barrel of a gun. i believe this is how harriet and ancestors who drowned themselves instead of being enslaved and jesus and buddha and people with kids who quit their jobs without knowing what’s next are all free in the same way.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;soooooooo this isn’t clean language yet but i believe that “those of us who are free love freedom so much that we will risk it to help others experience it.” and like harriet, that might mean slipping back into the territory of the unfree and leading others to freedom. this is both literal and physical and also a metaphor.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;patriarchy is particularly insidious because it (a) disconnects men (via traumatic experiences usually dealt by male friends and parents of all genders) from their bodies or sometimes even rewrites the helpful stance “i am settled, therefore i should move forward” into “i am unsettled, therefore i should move forward” (insert death-defying behaviors) and “i have no idea whether i’m settled or not, but i should do this thing anyways.” and (b) rewards people (see the cishet white wealthy risk-taking ceo and start-up founder and angel investor) who have done the most rewiring.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">a few quick quotes and thoughts i’m having while reading my grandmother’s hands by resmaa menakem.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">i am the perfect thing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/07/29/i-am-perfect/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="i am the perfect thing" /><published>2019-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/07/29/i-am-perfect</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/07/29/i-am-perfect/">&lt;p&gt;so something someone &lt;!-- owen thomas --&gt; said to me while during evolutionary relationships 1 was “you are the perfect thing! you are exactly what i need right now!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on monday july 22, a different friend &lt;!-- margie dillenburg --&gt; emailed me and said ‘You are perfect and right on time.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ok ok i get it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;edit: 30 july 2019 — and now dcc has added “you are the perfect human.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">so something someone said to me while during evolutionary relationships 1 was “you are the perfect thing! you are exactly what i need right now!”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">formation phase 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/07/18/entering-phase-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="formation phase 3" /><published>2019-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/07/18/entering-phase-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/07/18/entering-phase-3/">&lt;p&gt;we’re moving into the final phase of formation: it was originally called ‘beyond’ (following phase 1: inner, and phase 2: outer). now it’s called ‘inner-outer’ which is profounding confusing. but &amp;amp;shrug;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one of the first prompts we’re being called to is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Make time over the coming days to take stock of where you have been. Revisit your materials from the Discernment Period. What stands out now from the Healing Action Plan? What did you learn from reflecting on formation? From your conversations with your people? What did you say Yes to in January, and how has that played out? Start to notice threads running through your experience since then. Start to listen for an area you’re called toward in your life.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as i’ve started to do even a tiny bit of that reflection, so much is opening up! thoughts i’ve had so far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;what have i learned on reflection on formation so far?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WOW! when i think about current me compared to oct 2018 me, so much has changed. &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; in that funny non-dual way, so much is the same. but when i think about what i’m doing with my time, many things are different.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i’m so much better now at spending time solo. it’s clear now, beause of practice, why that time matters so much. it’s not selfish… it’s energizing to me and, by the transitive property, energizing for my community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i am holding spiritual circles now like… all over the place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the line between spiritual and non-spiritual circle is much blurrier than it was before.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;what have i learned from conversations with my people?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;having things i say said back to me is a huge way that i learn. luana did this first with the poem i wrote in response to one of the first prompts we got in the program. and danielle has done it to me most recently and in a way that totally blew my mind.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;what i haven’t done but still want to&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;heal wounds related to blackness (emotional emancipation group didn’t happen)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;transform relationship with dad (maybe do decolonizing christianity book club)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;explore gullah geechee ancestry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;explore other african ancestry and spiritual traditions (mali: dogon, root work)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">we’re moving into the final phase of formation: it was originally called ‘beyond’ (following phase 1: inner, and phase 2: outer). now it’s called ‘inner-outer’ which is profounding confusing. but &amp;amp;shrug;</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">evolutionary relationships 1 - launch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/journey/2019/07/15/journey-evolutionary-relationships-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="evolutionary relationships 1 - launch" /><published>2019-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/journey/2019/07/15/journey-evolutionary-relationships-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/journey/2019/07/15/journey-evolutionary-relationships-1/">&lt;p&gt;saturday july 13 was the launch of the 2 year evolutionary relationships cohort. i’m feeling honored to be a part of it. i am going to start a little notebook (or maybe continue an existing journey notebook… gah, i think i have my journey notes in like three different places. my bullet journals and two small notebooks for journeys but one is for drumming journeys and the other is for plant medicine journeys… why did i do that?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my intentions going in were &lt;em&gt;to be grounded and to let go.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;anyway, the crew is full of powerful-ass people and i’m so excited for it. it’s a journey to advance our collective consciousness so the real work/progress will be measured in the collective capacity but here are some individual insights that came through this time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;s.g.: “last time i saw you as a spider… this time, you’re a crow.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;speaking my vision repeatedly is how i get less contraction around it. — in convo with a.n.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sometimes i do healing without even realizing i’m doing it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“you are the perfect thing! you are exactly what i need right now.” — o.t.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“i think you would be a perfect e.d. for [the org you work at].” — dcc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;o.t. might be my post-patriarchy futures collaborator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i now have three concrete memories to explore and do some healing work around concerning childhood sexual trauma. maybe in future sessions with this group or maybe that is separate work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;integration thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;s.t. gave us the prompt: what ignites your heart? thoughts i had:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;knowing that the needs of my community are what turn on my magic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;knowing that i can be the perfect thing for someone, that i can be exactly what someone needs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;remembering that what got me to where i am isn’t going to get to me to where i’m going.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and some integration thoughts from other people…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;catalysts reduce the energy necessary for a reaction to occur. i/we are learning how to be catalysts. and there’s real biochemistry/mother earth to learn from here. — m.d.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wherever there is a gap in the me, it is filled by the we.” d.v.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if you don’t clear the brush, it just makes for a bigger fire later. — ecc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i also wanted to write up what my body is doing/did:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;while on this particular heart medicine, i always wreck the inside left of my jaw. next time, proactively ask for jaw support.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;afterwards, my body is definitely tired.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;so far, using this medicine i have yet to purge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i do notice a tightness or pressure in my stomach and lower belly before, during, and after.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;after i also have to frequently remind myself to breathe deeply. i catch myself breathing shallowly often.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;my temples are always sore 1-2, maybe 3 afterwards. lots of jaw movement happens during so that makes sense as an aftereffect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ok i think that’s it. thanks for traveling with me!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">saturday july 13 was the launch of the 2 year evolutionary relationships cohort. i’m feeling honored to be a part of it. i am going to start a little notebook (or maybe continue an existing journey notebook… gah, i think i have my journey notes in like three different places. my bullet journals and two small notebooks for journeys but one is for drumming journeys and the other is for plant medicine journeys… why did i do that?)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">shamanism journal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/07/07/shamanism-journal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="shamanism journal" /><published>2019-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/07/07/shamanism-journal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/07/07/shamanism-journal/">&lt;p&gt;readings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;http://www.shamanicjourney.com/history-of-shamanism&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://jeremiahstanghini.com/2013/08/05/the-history-of-shamanism-a-brief-overview-of-shamanism-part-1/&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://www.gaia.com/article/how-much-do-you-know-about-shamanism&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://www.refinery29.com/en-us/2017/01/136659/what-is-a-shaman-definition-spiritual-healer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;voodoo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/what-is-vodou_b_827947&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hoodoo rootwork:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;https://www.originalbotanica.com/blog/a-beginners-guide-to-hoodoo-rootwork/&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;chinese shamanism - &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chinese_shamanism&quot;&gt;wuism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;notes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;libations are one of the most common elements
can be simple or one day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;liquid (alcohol or water or other) poured on the earth to honor the relationships we have with each others, the earth, animals. it brings them in and manifests our intentions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;connecting to fellow humans and fellow spirits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we recognize our resposibility to those future generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;shamanism is practices and a worldview&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;each tradition has a different definition of what spirits are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tungus term shamam means ‘one who is raised’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for djaloki&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;spirits are invisible beings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;shamanism is spirit intelligence. the goal is to make relationships with invisible beings work for us and the spirits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;african voodoo comes from benin/togo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“everything fits in shamanism.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;magic is a tricky word because people who do illusions in english are called magicians. but there is magic beyond illusions, tho illusions may also be magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;magic: accessing the invisible thru visible means or accessing the visible thorugh invisible means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;symbolism,analogies, metaphors, synchronicities - these are things that translate from spirits into language that humans can understand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;alchemy has a principle of sublimation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;things that go direction from solid to gas. sage, incense, tobacco. these things represent the spiritualization of matter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;the sage, when it’s here in leaf form it’s here. but once it’s gas, it’s everywhere.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;why do shamanic journey&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;increase awareness and relationship&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it’s fun&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gives me more health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;https://m.wikihow.com/Lucid-Dream&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">readings:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">labyrinths and a gift from one</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/06/27/labyrinths-and-a-gift/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="labyrinths and a gift from one" /><published>2019-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/06/27/labyrinths-and-a-gift</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/06/27/labyrinths-and-a-gift/">&lt;p&gt;i think i had forgotten this but i’m super into labyrinths. there have been labyrinths at the site of the advanced training i was at back in april with css, there were two at the location of the united for a fair economy training of trainers location in north andover, there were two (though i only found one) at the garrison institute for waking up fabulous, and there are two where i am now at the site of our css staff retreat (in san anselmo on a satellite campus of the sf theological seminary). [insert photos] there’s a sci-fi story in here somewhere about the connections between labyrinths…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;second note: i walked one of them yesterday with two co-workers and i walked the second one today for some grounding after a really hard moment on retreat. there’s probably more to say on that but that’s not what i wanted to say here… when i got to the center of the labyrinth, i found that people had left two stones/crystals, a heart pendant, and a bundle of (now dry) flowers. i wanted to leave something but i didn’t want to leave the stone or crystal i was carrying. i decided to leave nothing and was feeling kind of guilty about it. but on my way out i started picking up trash and then had the thought: “oh sometimes the gift one brings can be the removal of something.” and upon further reflection, i think that’s what a lot of healing work (especially when embedded in community) is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;anyway, that’s all for now. gotta go finish some work before bed!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">i think i had forgotten this but i’m super into labyrinths. there have been labyrinths at the site of the advanced training i was at back in april with css, there were two at the location of the united for a fair economy training of trainers location in north andover, there were two (though i only found one) at the garrison institute for waking up fabulous, and there are two where i am now at the site of our css staff retreat (in san anselmo on a satellite campus of the sf theological seminary). [insert photos] there’s a sci-fi story in here somewhere about the connections between labyrinths…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">june tarot readings</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/06/26/june-tarot-readings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="june tarot readings" /><published>2019-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/06/26/june-tarot-readings</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/06/26/june-tarot-readings/">&lt;p&gt;so i’m at the june 2019 css staff retreat and i have done two tarot readings, one yesterday and one today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;yesteday’s reading was totally fine and i think it was useful for the recipient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;just now though i did a reading that felt on fire. but, unsurprisingly, i think it had everything to do with the recipient. i also gave a presentation earlier today (each staff person gives a 15 min short presentation each retreat about a topic of their choosing that blurs the line between the personal and professional) on my formation work and how it relates to my job at the org. one of the 10 slides was about my tarot practice and i think that might have also had something to do with the recipient being receptive to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;also she said she has been avoiding her clairvoyant abilities for her whole life. so there’s that too lol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;anyway, it seemed like the reading unlocked lots for her and i felt a new level of access to my intuitive depth. and even in the 20 minutes after the reading, she texted me a breakthrough and real integration she’s had. it seems real.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;super pumped about it! more readings coming up later this week for other staff members (at least two). we’ll see how they go…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">so i’m at the june 2019 css staff retreat and i have done two tarot readings, one yesterday and one today.</summary></entry></feed>