<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-07T00:07:22-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/feed.xml</id><title type="html">lqb2 spiritual formation (project)</title><subtitle>this is me following my own journey and sharing it with you</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Horoscopes for the New Moon in Pisces – March 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/horoscope/2019/03/06/new-moon-in-pisces/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Horoscopes for the New Moon in Pisces – March 2019" /><published>2019-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/horoscope/2019/03/06/new-moon-in-pisces</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/horoscope/2019/03/06/new-moon-in-pisces/">&lt;p&gt;source: https://chaninicholas.com/new-moon-pisces-march-2019/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;aries&quot;&gt;Aries&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;basic personality &amp;amp; ego&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memories, and the emotions attached to them bring information that I never refuse. &lt;strong&gt;Timing is everything and any part of my past that is being recovered right now is worth investigating.&lt;/strong&gt;  Even briefly. &lt;strong&gt;I know not to hang on to what is moving through me, but I also know not to resist the current.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am both the container for my experience and the witness of how it pours forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Like water overflowing, I allow my imagination to play with the possibilities of what it looks like to live into, through, and beyond the stories of my life.&lt;/strong&gt; To survive is to defy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I allow to define me is my choice, my point of power, and my right to change when and where I need to. With this new moon I am reminded to take note of what I am calling myself, how I am referring to myself, and what that infers to myself. I am here for my liberation, and &lt;em&gt;anything that needs to be released on the way to my personal freedom must be given back to its owner&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Within the incubators that house my creative energy I give myself permission to regenerate. Here I reclaim myself, rename myself if need be, and remember that I am always becoming&lt;/strong&gt;, undefined by what has happened to me or hasn’t happened for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;aquarius-rising&quot;&gt;Aquarius Rising&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;how others experience me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is mine to work with has always been and will always be.  I need not fight it, push it, or feel like someone else can take it from me. My resources may take their own time to develop, but they deserve every second they need to take shape. I trust that when the tide ebbs it will flow again. I trust that the projects that wash up on shore are gifts for me to develop. I know that anything that gets lost at sea need not concern me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am here to work on what is in front of me.&lt;/strong&gt; No fantasy. Just the reality of working towards my dreams with every solid, grounded,  effort I can make. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I no longer place my talent, time, and resources into containers too leaky to hold them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Ideas without action aren’t failures, they are foolish to focus on. If I want it, I work towards it. Inwardly and outwardly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’m healing my relationship to my financial life no matter the damage, drain, or despair that I’ve experienced because of it. I am not at the whim of my livelihood, but the curator in relationship with it and all it might be able to do.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;virgo&quot;&gt;Virgo&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;moon: inner self &amp;amp; deepest emotions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am made stronger by every moment of vulnerability I have allowed myself.&lt;/strong&gt; Even when I’m met with less warmth than I’d hoped from others, I’m still fortified by my own efforts. &lt;strong&gt;Being honest in front of others takes courage.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;I am willing to look like a human who makes both mistakes and as many attempts to get it right as it requires. I am willing to be humbled by all that I still need to learn.&lt;/strong&gt; I am willing to be misunderstood on the way to being known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m in no rush to be right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My relationships require me to learn how to be open to my own experience when I’d rather shut down, shut you out, or shut the door completely. &lt;em&gt;When I am able to hang out in the moments of wanting to do so, without actually doing so, I know that growth is occurring.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I know that change is possible. I know that from this place all the information I need becomes available to me. &lt;strong&gt;With much change on the horizon, I know that developing the skills to sit with what’s uncertain and uncomfortable is more than useful, it’s the most reliable compass I’ll ever have contact with.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;cancer&quot;&gt;Cancer&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;chiron description from &lt;a href=&quot;https://cafeastrology.com/chiron.html&quot;&gt;cafe astrology&lt;/a&gt;. shout out to luana for suggesting i look up where chiron is in my chart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Chiron is a comet with a unique and erratic orbit. In the natal chart, Chiron is symbolized by the “wounded healer”. It represents our deepest wound, and our efforts to heal the wound. Chiron was named after the centaur in Greek mythology who was a healer and teacher who, ironically, could not heal himself.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Chiron in Astrology: Chiron in our natal charts points to where we have healing powers as the result of our own deep spiritual wounds. We may over-compensate in these areas of life. Chiron, as a wounded healer, first must face issues of low self-worth and feelings of inadequacy and learn to rise above these issues. Because the wound goes deep, and we may work hard to overcome the wound, healing powers are potent.”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I honor the editing process that I am in. Like weeding an overgrown garden, I remove what is unhelpful in order to bring out the beauty naturally present.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I work with this new moon to clear what clutters my path.&lt;/strong&gt; Doubts that have no sense need to be dumped. Fears that have no foundation need to be exposed as the frauds that they are.  &lt;strong&gt;Shame that no longer serves a purpose needs to be shown the door. This clearing is mine to do. It can’t be shopped out, left for another, or put off.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This helps me take responsibility for the direction I am heading in, but it also helps me feel empowered in the process of doing so. The more I own my desire to head in the direction of my dreams, the less likely I am to resent the work necessary to get there.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;With this new moon I claim the path that I am on&lt;/strong&gt;, all that it asks of me, and all that it asks me to give up, miss out on, or forgo for it. I am crystal clear about the price and that the payoff is to merely be in this process with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I use this Mercury retrograde to review my strategies, maps, and ways of getting from point A to B, making sure that they leave me open to get all the way to Z.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">source: https://chaninicholas.com/new-moon-pisces-march-2019/</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">tarot synchronicity as i prepare for journey work</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/03/04/tarot-synchronicity/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="tarot synchronicity as i prepare for journey work" /><published>2019-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/03/04/tarot-synchronicity</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/03/04/tarot-synchronicity/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/hcUTLxs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;last week, on feb 27 i pulled the sun. on feb 28, i pulled the king of swords reversed. on march 1, i pulled them both. well, the sun fell out while i was shuffling and i pulled the king of swords reversed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;clearly this is a message i need to hear: the sun’s light turned inward to my own truth. i have been doing lots of intention setting and prep for my march 10 medicine journey work and i think this is a signal for that. so excited!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">resources about loneliness</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/03/01/loneliness/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="resources about loneliness" /><published>2019-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/03/01/loneliness</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/03/01/loneliness/">&lt;p&gt;i’m collecting articles and resources on loneliness for two friends. my thinking: loneliness IS part of the human experience. by looking at it and becoming friends with it and its unavoidability, we tap into the reality that we are deeply unalone because we are part of the universe. but i’m looking for ways to help share that with friends who don’t see that yet or that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theweek.com/articles/798959/history-loneliness&quot;&gt;The history of loneliness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://theconversation.com/a-history-of-loneliness-91542&quot;&gt;The Conversation: A history of loneliness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- for chad and jacobo --&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">i’m collecting articles and resources on loneliness for two friends. my thinking: loneliness IS part of the human experience. by looking at it and becoming friends with it and its unavoidability, we tap into the reality that we are deeply unalone because we are part of the universe. but i’m looking for ways to help share that with friends who don’t see that yet or that way.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">bodhisattva journey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/02/28/Bodhisattva-journey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="bodhisattva journey" /><published>2019-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/02/28/Bodhisattva-journey</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/02/28/Bodhisattva-journey/">&lt;p&gt;last night, i was talking to my buddy, jacobo, and he off-hand said “hey, man, i just want to support your bodhisattva journey!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and idk but i really appreciated that gift. now i have a new way (and a new term) to be thinking about my spiritual formation process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">last night, i was talking to my buddy, jacobo, and he off-hand said “hey, man, i just want to support your bodhisattva journey!”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">notes from the wounder healer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/23/the-wounder-healer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="notes from the wounder healer" /><published>2019-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/23/the-wounder-healer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/23/the-wounder-healer/">&lt;p&gt;i started reading the wounded healer a few days ago when it arrived. it is a killer of a book. i’ll ask my assistant to process all the highlights from it when he’s back from his magical vacation with his booface, but until there, i’ll just share a few that really struck me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Mysticism and revolution are two aspects of the same attempt to bring about radical change. Mystics cannot prevent themselves from becoming social critics, since in self-reflection they will discover the roots of a sick society. Similarly, revolutionaries cannot avoid facing their own human condition, since in the midst of their struggle for a new world they will find that they are also fighting their own reactionary fears and false ambitions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When we wonder why the language of tradition Christianity has lost its liberation power for nuclear man, we have to realize that most Christian preaching is still based on the presupposition that man sees himself as meaningfully integrated with a history in which God came to us in the past, is living under us in the present, and will come to liberate us in the future. But when man’s historical consciousness is broken, the whole Christian message seems like a lecture about the great pioneers to a boy on an acid trip.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(and the next paragraph of the above quote)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But how can we avoid this danger? I think by no other way than to enter ourselves first of all into the center of our existence and become familiar with the complexities of our inner lives. As soon as we feel at home in our own house, discover the dark corners as well as the light spots, the closed doors as well as the drafty roos, our confusion will evaporate, our anxiety will diminish, and we will become capable of creative work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i love that one because it’s my new definition and purpose for doing shadow work (which i’ve been talking to some of yall about). i’m adding these words to words already in my mind/heart that two of yall have shared with me. &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But just as bread given without love can bring war instead of peace, professionalism without compassion will turn forgiveness into a gimmick, and the kingdon to come into a blindfold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">i started reading the wounded healer a few days ago when it arrived. it is a killer of a book. i’ll ask my assistant to process all the highlights from it when he’s back from his magical vacation with his booface, but until there, i’ll just share a few that really struck me:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">you could never…</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/02/18/you-could-never/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="you could never..." /><published>2019-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/02/18/you-could-never</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/02/18/you-could-never/">&lt;p&gt;story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the other day i was sitting in the barbershop texting kendra. we were talking about scheduling a phone call and i was being all sorts of weird about it. i realized this in hindsight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;she asked me for some dates that worked during a particular week. i responded with a message about being out of town for three days that week. then the below conversation ensued…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/aZoqaud.png&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as i worked through my own stuff, kendra saw that last message from me and then said something that literally rocked my world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/JMHgjkZ.png&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i teared up right then and there in the barbershop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i didn’t realize how tightly i hold onto my fear of disappointing other people!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;kendra and i texted some more and she said (paraphrased) “given what you said, i could feel that you needed to hear that from me. don’t ever worry about disappointing me, and especially not when you’re taking space to do what you need to do for yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ho. lee. shit. i am leveled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gonna be sitting with this for some days/weeks/months. how many situations in my life are shaped by this belief of mine?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i will shift it in time, but for now, just noticing and reflecting… wow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">story.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Horoscopes for the New Moon in Aquarius – February 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/horoscope/2019/02/17/new-moon-in-aquarius/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Horoscopes for the New Moon in Aquarius – February 2019" /><published>2019-02-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/horoscope/2019/02/17/new-moon-in-aquarius</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/horoscope/2019/02/17/new-moon-in-aquarius/">&lt;p&gt;source: https://chaninicholas.com/new-moon-aquarius-2019-horoscopes/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;aries&quot;&gt;Aries&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;basic personality &amp;amp; ego&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aligning myself with the people, places, and actions that bring me closer to my dreams is my main priority. There are a million distractions, doubts, and fears to get caught up in daily.&lt;/strong&gt; There are a million ways in which I have been taught to devalue my vision, to denigrate it, to convince myself that I am not the answer to it as much as it is to me. &lt;strong&gt;But my destiny is to be met on a two-way street.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It needs me to make room for it every day. Aligning myself with what I most want to manifest is something I have to consciously do. Repeatedly. Daily.&lt;/strong&gt; Enthusiastically if possible. Honestly, always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I am being truthful, &lt;strong&gt;when unchecked I will tend to grasp for what might make my ego momentarily happy&lt;/strong&gt;. A place. A thing. A person. An idea of success, love, or acceptance. But &lt;strong&gt;unless achieved in a way that deepens my connection to myself, my loves, my life, and my world, nothing will satisfy my soul’s desire to do good work with good people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I want to know what it means to feel aligned with my life’s purpose&lt;/strong&gt; so deeply that I never refuse the challenges, victories and defeats along the way. &lt;strong&gt;I don’t waste my time chasing fool’s gold.&lt;/strong&gt; I want the glimmer to be inner, first and foremost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;aquarius-rising&quot;&gt;Aquarius Rising&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;how others experience me&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am renewed each time I allow myself to move thoroughly through a process. Each time I allow myself to reach the bottom, to ground, to land. Bouncing back is not necessarily the end-game, but unless I get to the bottom of things, I’ll never be able to.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Each time I allow myself to look up.&lt;/strong&gt; Stretch up. Rise up towards the light. &lt;strong&gt;I am refusing to stay in the shadows of my past.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Each time I allow myself the luxury of cycling through my process without feeling rushed or overly attached to any one part of it, my energy is regenerated.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am renewed each time I remember that life is not something I figure out, but something I find a way to be in partnership with.&lt;/strong&gt; Each time I try to pin my possibilities down into a definite answer, I am deadening the energy of everything else that is trying to flow towards me. &lt;strong&gt;With this new moon I release the need to know how, what, where, or with whom things will work out&lt;/strong&gt; and instead I focus on the direction I feel pulled towards in this moment. &lt;strong&gt;Every time I gather my energy, recalling it from the past, I am reinvesting in myself, this moment, and all the possibility it possesses.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;virgo&quot;&gt;Virgo&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;moon: inner self &amp;amp; deepest emotions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I find every avenue possible to love the labor.&lt;/strong&gt; As much as I take advantage of rest. As much as I honor my downtime. As much as I revel in my free-time, to the best of my ability I find things to adore about my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I want bounty to come from my efforts, I have to make peace with the practice that goes into creating it. &lt;strong&gt;The secret to my success is loving the process&lt;/strong&gt;, not just the performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I leave room for opportunity. &lt;strong&gt;I remember not to get too rigid in how I think my work or efforts will be received, what they will amount to, or where they will go.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;I work in ways that help to regenerate my creative energy.&lt;/strong&gt; I work in ways that keep me focus on the reasons that I do what I do. &lt;strong&gt;To the best of my ability, I clear out what leaves me feeling cluttered, muddled, or confused about my direction.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am here to work towards what will bring the most joy and healing to the most people, places, and causes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">source: https://chaninicholas.com/new-moon-aquarius-2019-horoscopes/</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">a walk in the arboretum</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/02/17/known-and-unknown/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a walk in the arboretum" /><published>2019-02-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/02/17/known-and-unknown</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/insight/2019/02/17/known-and-unknown/">&lt;p&gt;this write up is more brief than the weight it carries, but i’ve been trying to write it for three days and not doing it because i’m overblowing the time it needs in my mind. working on moving through that by sharing here in short:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;last week i committed to a bringing a new spiritual practice into my regular ritual flows. i guess it’s actually just a modification, but i’m going to shift my usual saturday 1h sitting meditation into a Spirit walk. ideally it’ll be through the arnold arboretum, but wherever i can find some nature will do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;today, i went on my first one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it was prompted because i was going to be hosting full moon circle later and the last time i held one, i did 1h in the arb and it felt like what was needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so today i walked in my usual gate and felt drawn to a path i’ve often looked at but had never taken before. as i walked, i reveled in getting to know the new territory. and soon enough, i found myself near the shrub and vine collect where the bonsai collection is (learning: the bonsai collection is only available outdoors april - nov)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as i stumbled onto that familar place i was reminded that i love that sensation! the feel of finding my way to a place i know but from a totally new angle. i love love love when this happens in cities! often when i’m new to a city i’ll see lots of it for starters and then i’ll settle into areas near where i live and get to know those areas really well. then, as i start to expand and explore again, i’ll find myself back to places i visited early on but didn’t realize how they connected to my usual pathways. it’s the “omg THAT’S where this road goes” moment. i literally love those moments…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and then it dawned on me: that’s what deep internal work looks and feels like. the work of self-exploration and also integration is just the process of exploring the unknown paths between known areas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;phew. maybe that was a lot more intense in my head or for me than it is for you, but it feels like a major breakthrough for me! :D&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">this write up is more brief than the weight it carries, but i’ve been trying to write it for three days and not doing it because i’m overblowing the time it needs in my mind. working on moving through that by sharing here in short:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">how to love me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/horoscope/2019/02/15/how-to-love-me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="how to love me" /><published>2019-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/horoscope/2019/02/15/how-to-love-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/horoscope/2019/02/15/how-to-love-me/">&lt;p&gt;thanks, luana, for sharing this. every bit of this felt relevant. holy cow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;source: https://chaninicholas.com/love-horoscopes-february-2019/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love is a risk. Love is a loss. Love is a revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love makes clear every fear we must work through. Love brings with it every reason to make such effort. Love initiates us, leaving us forever changed, forever marked, forever awakened to what could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The love we cultivate, the love we elevate, the love we choose to accentuate speaks volumes about who we are and how we define our lives.  Love isn’t romance alone, but the most platonic of relationships can be the most romantic. Love is the only thing worth decorating oneself, and ones life, with and for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love needs to be at the center of all we do if we are to do it for long. Love needs our actions because it starves on words alone. Love needs our solidarity because it shrivels up in isolation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This world has no shortages of opportunities to demonstrate love out loud. May we use each one that comes our way. May our love crack the shields that loneliness creates. May our actions create more spaces for love to flourish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week’s horoscopes are (reworked and) republished from February 2017, I hope they still serve you well. They were, and are, written as inspirations to help us understand, accept, and possibly love each other, and ourselves, a little better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sign that the sun was in when we were born is only one part of our astrological chart, far from the whole of it. You may therefore, want to read the horoscope for the signs that your sun, moon, rising, and Venus are in, for yourself and your loved ones. You’ll know which parts of each of them resonate with you the most, as always, leave the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;aries-my-sun-sign&quot;&gt;Aries (my sun sign)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love the fire. Love the passion. Love the energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love them like they are or leave them alone. Love them without asking them to stay in one place. Love them for all that they stir up. Love them for the energy that they have to channel day in and day out. Like a live wire, Aries possesses a tremendous wattage. That’s no easy task. It can leave one burnt out, freaked out or on fire with the latest inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They need many outlets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They need indirect encouragement to focus on the activities that are productive and proactive. They need to find solutions to their problems themselves or they won’t respect what they have won.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you love an Aries, love the way they set themselves and life into motion. Love the way they fill empty space with their energy. Love the way they burst onto the scene. Without thinking about the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love them through every scuffle but refuse to let them pick a fight with you just to let off steam. Love them through the wild bouts of energy that they are asked to manage but don’t let their style steamroll your own needs. Love the fact that they are willing to test the limits of their heart through the boundaries of the relationship they are in with you. Hold them accountable. They will love you all the more for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love their bravery and their ability to encourage your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be a worthy opponent by being honest and unwilling to be bossed. Be willing to push back out of a deep dedication to your love for them. Be dedicated to your own independence and let your relationship with them be a testament to what can happen when people come together to honor one another’s spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;virgo-my-moon&quot;&gt;Virgo (my moon)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love the precision. Love the thoughtfulness. Love the sincerity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To love a Virgo is to love that they may not know how to leave well enough alone. Love that they may not know how to let go when there are jobs left undone. Love that they may want to sort instead of consort until there’s quality company to be had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notice the work that they have done to make your life easier. Applaud them for the carefully curated problem solving they have provided for you. Make an effort to understand how their worry manifests. Hyper-criticism will arise when they feel unsafe, unsettled, or unfulfilled. Rather than engaging with the critique, engage with the underlying stressor. Let them know that you are holding their story with them. Following the plot. Connecting the dots. Ready to work it out at a moment’s notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Virgo understands your ability to roll up your sleeves and put the effort in, the well-earned, hard-won respect you get from them is no ordinary praise. Virgo can be demanding, but Virgo will never forget your favorites, your needs, and your necessities. They might not call for your attention all the time, but once you get theirs, they’ll make a ritual out of reminding you how special you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;aquarius-my-rising&quot;&gt;Aquarius (my rising)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love the clarity. Love the certainty. Love the strength that they constantly communicate to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love their ability to care more about getting their point across than pandering to the feelings of those in power. Nothing impresses this sign save for the ability to think for oneself. Not swayed by public opinion, able to see past the fears that most humans let their thinking get bound up in, Aquarius aims for the truth and will pick you when they know that you are it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be loved by an Aquarius is to be respected. To be loved by an Aquarius is to be loved for your own merit. To be loved by an Aquarius is to be loved out of choice, never out of duty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To love an Aquarius is to love being constantly astounded by how quickly they understand a system, situation or subtlety. To love an Aquarius means introducing them to the fact that facts sometimes can hurt your feelings. Facts don’t always need to be the first thing spoken. Some hearts need time to adjust to the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To love and be loved by Aquarius means that autonomy is a turn on for you both, and space is sacred, necessary, and needed if the embers of the heart are to be kept alive and aglow.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">thanks, luana, for sharing this. every bit of this felt relevant. holy cow.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">shame</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/13/shame/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="shame" /><published>2019-02-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/13/shame</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/13/shame/">&lt;p&gt;what’s coming up for me right now? shame! holy cow is it coming up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i shifted my daily gratitude journal to a daily shame journal for now just to pay more attention to it. i don’t stay here forever but i do want to begin to notice patterns so i can intervene on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;also some links:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;https://www.goodreads.com/shelf/show/shame&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://healingshame.com/about/&quot;&gt;center for healing shame&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://healingshame.com/self-help/&quot;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">what’s coming up for me right now? shame! holy cow is it coming up.</summary></entry></feed>