<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-03T10:18:48-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/feed.xml</id><title type="html">lqb2 spiritual formation (project)</title><subtitle>this is me following my own journey and sharing it with you</subtitle><entry><title type="html">avoidance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/03/avoidance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="avoidance" /><published>2019-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/03/avoidance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/03/avoidance/">&lt;p&gt;so!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here we are at my first moment of truth. this is me being vulnerable not knowing where this is  going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;yesterday, i pulled the moon (reversed) and the 8 of swords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/RLa62yE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;whether you know tarot or not, here are some intepretation thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the moon, in one way, is about working with the imagination and dreams (sometimes pleasant, sometimes terrifying). working with these things, where our shadows are, can generate fear because the things there are unknown. the moon reversed says that one is avoiding looking at the darkness. and then the 8 of swords is about blockage that isn’t actually forcefully holding the captive. the woman behind the swords isn’t actually locked in by then. she could walk around them if she wanted… but she has not yet taken that step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;today, i pulled the world, also reversed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the world is about the supreme, divine union of unconscious, consciousness, and super-conscious, then blending of secular and spiritual, the merging of earth and heaven. and the union results in a dance. the truth revealed there to me is that the universe IS about movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when reversed, the message is stagnation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;today and yesterday all point to two things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i am avoiding my shadow work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the way i avoid it is simple: by not taking &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s become clear to me in the last week &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; being busy is so detrimental to my life’s work: it allows me to avoid being with myself. and since i am the only vessel through which particular medicine can flow, if i don’t know how to be with myself, how will i know how to work with my magic?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;as i say that it sounds extreme, but i guess what i really mean is that this is a moment to do some deep work and i need time and space to sit with it to do it. which means i’m at another moment of needing to clear some space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i’ve been through this many times before and i have strong muscles around saying no… but it seems they need to get even stronger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i feel good about my ability to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;what i don’t feel good about how to start taking steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my ask to you: when you know where you’re headed but you are stuck, what do you do to get yourself unstuck? how do you take a step forward?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">so!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">libations (part 2)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/03/libations-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="libations (part 2)" /><published>2019-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/03/libations-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/03/libations-2/">&lt;p&gt;i found another blog post on libations: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gyenyamejourney.com/2011/04/how-to-pour-libations.html&quot;&gt;gye-nyame journey: how to pour libations&lt;/a&gt;. there’s a really helpful narration of verbal libations that i’m going to do for a week or so with my tarot pulls and see what happens. the words for the libations are down below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;also, something i learned from that author is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Libations are very serious, because when we do them we invite the Universal axe’ (spirit) to be active in the room. We must realize that this axe’ is always present, but when we consciously call it into our presence we have the opportunity to bless ourselves and others. If we play with it we can do great harm to ourselves and everyone in the room. If the leader of the ritual is not focused and consciously calls this energy into a room that is not ready it is like having a energy surge in your house, a fuse can be blown. But  instead of the lights going out in the house (which they can), the metaphoric lights in some of the participants lives go out (unbalanced events can begin to happen).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so now i’ve shifted my daily question from “what do i need to know today?” to “ancestors, what do i need to know today?” it’s a seemingly tiny shift, but my pulls yesterday and today already feel different and more powerful. probably partly because of my intentionality and partly because Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reality really does seem to be what we make it. hm!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the presence of our all powerful, all knowing, and all present Creator by what ever name you call It we Pour
AXE’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pour for our Celestial ancestors known in different cultures by different names. to some they are known as Orisha, to some they are known as Neteru, to some Angels we pour for them
AXE’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the presence of our ancient ancestors. Those that existed before our Maafa. those that existed before our captivity… feel free to call names….we pour
AXE’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the presence of our ancestors who died during the middle passage and our Maafa, we pour…..
AXE’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pour for Universal Ancestors. The One’s that researched and taught us who we are. those freedom fighters that stood for what was and is right…. feel free to call names….. we pour…
AXE’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pour for our Personal ancestors. Those who gave birth to us, nurtured us and taught us. feel free to call names….. we pour
AXE’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pour to welcome the the present moment. We salute the power of the moment, and salute the the ever present now….we pour
AXE’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pour for our future generations. We remember them now and build for them, so that they can one day pour for us…we pour
AXE’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pour to the seven directions to west, north, east, south, the up, the down and we pour for the center which dwells in each of us…we pour
AXE’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pour for the 5 elements , we pour for the fire, earth, air, water, and the life that they all combine and make… we pour
AXE’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pour for each individual here and any issues that you would like to share feel free to shout them out….. we pour 
AXE’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings us back to where we started. We began with the Creator and we end with the Creator we pour 3 times …….
AXE’ AXE’ AXE’&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">i found another blog post on libations: gye-nyame journey: how to pour libations. there’s a really helpful narration of verbal libations that i’m going to do for a week or so with my tarot pulls and see what happens. the words for the libations are down below.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">libations</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/01/libations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="libations" /><published>2019-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/01/libations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/02/01/libations/">&lt;p&gt;today begins black history/futures month. excited for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i want to learn about libations (singular? plural?) so i’m starting to do that as the ritual practice before i shuffle my tarot deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i read &lt;a href=&quot;https://globalfaithministriesofchiism.wordpress.com/2012/05/04/libations-itu-mmai-7/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; about the practice of libations but i want more. if you know anything, would you please share or point me to another resource?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;finally, in honor of black history/futures month, i think i want to commit to writing flash fiction related to me and my lineage(s) every day. maybe it’s one story with many entries. maybe they’ll all be separate. who knows. either way, time to get writing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">today begins black history/futures month. excited for that.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">27 jan 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/27/jan-27/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="27 jan 2019" /><published>2019-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/27/jan-27</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/27/jan-27/">&lt;p&gt;wanted to share my current morning tarot ritual/routine with yall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;meditate for 10 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;opening the four directions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;shuffle and hold the query: what do i need to know about today?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;contemplate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;read 78 degrees of wisdom description&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;journal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/qyY9SnV.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;meditate for 10 mins&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;close&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/qWkkl6O.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imgur&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">wanted to share my current morning tarot ritual/routine with yall.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">26 jan 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/26/jan-26/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="26 jan 2019" /><published>2019-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/26/jan-26</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/26/jan-26/">&lt;p&gt;tonight i got in a (union) taxi to get home from the airport. within a few words of conversation, the driver (pema (sp?)) looked back at me and said, “hmmm! you seem like you’re very present-minded right now. your smile, your eyes, you seem like an enlightened soul… am i right or is that a stretch?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;floored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;he proceeded to tell me he was tibetan, buddhist (but not in the religious sense) and that i seemed like a person who could tap into bliss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mind. blown.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">tonight i got in a (union) taxi to get home from the airport. within a few words of conversation, the driver (pema (sp?)) looked back at me and said, “hmmm! you seem like you’re very present-minded right now. your smile, your eyes, you seem like an enlightened soul… am i right or is that a stretch?”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">24 jan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/24/jan-24/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="24 jan" /><published>2019-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/24/jan-24</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/24/jan-24/">&lt;p&gt;today i finished a 1.5 day consulting gig. on the way out, one of the people in the group &lt;!-- tony parchment --&gt; said two things to me worth noting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;during the closing circle he tony parchment said “i’m so thoroughly impressed by how you present yourself at your age. how old did you say you are? 27? 29? when i was your age, i wasn’t nearly as thoughtful or well-put-together as you are. wow!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on the way out of drinks, he says “thanks for facilitating for us. you’re an old, old soul.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;:O&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">today i finished a 1.5 day consulting gig. on the way out, one of the people in the group said two things to me worth noting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">saying yes to formation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/12/yes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="saying yes to formation" /><published>2019-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/12/yes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/12/yes/">&lt;p&gt;I, Lawrence Barriner II, brother to Laurentius, child of Jacqueline and Lawrence (by blood), grandchild of Ruth (by blood), Martin (by love), William (by blood), Carrie (by love), James (by love), Doretha (by blood) and Henry (by blood), descendent of Gilbert Maynor, born 1813, of Charleston, South Carolina, godfather of Asa, uncle of Jayden, Apollo, Alvie, and Leah, and inspired by the powerful work and lineages of Boston facilitators and healers, queer Christian mystics, theologians, writers, and poets…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commit&lt;/strong&gt;
Say yes to this nine months transformation, supported by deep introspection, self- and community-care, healing/integration, and love. This commitment to my transformation is in support of my own movement towards liberation which, in turn and simultaneously is a necessary driver and element of liberation for our species (and beyond). In order to authentically use my gift / responsibility (supporting transformation), I must have the experience of my own transformation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Practice&lt;/strong&gt;
I will remind myself of my commitment by reading it aloud weekly, ideally during Sabbath. 
I will document my process weekly (maybe as a way to break my Sabbath) by writing and taking photos to share with my small group as well as my formation team. 
I will work with tarot daily. 
I will engage in journey work with plant medicine. 
I will meditate daily for 20+ minutes and have at least one 60 minute session per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support and Inspiration&lt;/strong&gt;
I know that this will not be easy. I will remember to return to my commitment when I struggle or want to back out of this work. I will preemptively ask my elder to check in on me every two weeks. I will make sure that my formation small group and team knows my telltale signs of struggle and avoidance: poor time-management, lack of high-quality sleep, and under-communication about what is happening. When I feel overwhelmed, I will scale back to my minimum viable ritual: meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To What End&lt;/strong&gt;
I make this commitment with my whole heart, knowing it may involve unforeseen challenges and disruption to the life I have known. It is worth doing because the gift, the medicine I have is useless unless it is shared. I have seen previous iterations of impact when I am doing my work in the world and now it is time to level up. Why now? The increasingly chaotic world we live in will require everything we have if our species is going to survive. I recognize and accept that the survival our species is not a necessity; species go extinct all the time. ‘Everything we have’ includes what I have and I am ready to step even farther into what that is so that I can play my part in this beautiful, universal love song of life and death.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I, Lawrence Barriner II, brother to Laurentius, child of Jacqueline and Lawrence (by blood), grandchild of Ruth (by blood), Martin (by love), William (by blood), Carrie (by love), James (by love), Doretha (by blood) and Henry (by blood), descendent of Gilbert Maynor, born 1813, of Charleston, South Carolina, godfather of Asa, uncle of Jayden, Apollo, Alvie, and Leah, and inspired by the powerful work and lineages of Boston facilitators and healers, queer Christian mystics, theologians, writers, and poets…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">on beginning formation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/06/beginning-formation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="on beginning formation" /><published>2019-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/06/beginning-formation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/formation/general/2019/01/06/beginning-formation/">&lt;p&gt;1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i am love: stardust, gravity, matter 
i, matter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i am the love of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i know i am because when i say it, i shake 
my skin tingles 
my heart pounds
i want to cover my mouth 
but i remember that i am
and so i do not&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;because when i remember that i am
power beyond my limits arrives
it was always here
always
but i forgot
forget&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and so my work
is to remember&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and you? 
when you say it? 
maybe your hands will also shake 
or 
maybe these words 
are not rooted in you
as they are in me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but if you are here
facing yourself (the Universe)
then there are words rooted in you that will make you shake
where are they?
ah, is that their light we see
coming through the seams?
what are they?
let us open them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we/all will know when you have
the ocean has a funny way of finding us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to integrate is to bring the pieces together&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after traveling, a trip, a journey
integration is 
bringing from the mountaintop
what we can use in the valley&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and so we work
in the valley
hoping to return to the highest points
with more than we brought last time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;healing is partnership
with ourselves
with each other
with the Universe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i am
you are
we are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;let you/me/us
remember&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">1.</summary></entry></feed>